The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Thirty-Ninth Episode
The Stolen Beauty
- They say the Queen is sick.
- And seriously so, it seems!
Are there no cures
for this illness?
I'm sorry, sir, but it
seems there are none.
Something she ate
must have made her sick!
I don't think so.
Anyway, food poisoning...
...is a very dangerous thing.
- I heard she has a high fever!
Many doctors have examined her,
but no one has managed to cure her.
I feel very sorry for
her She is still so young!
What do I hear!
The Queen... is sick!
I wonder if there are any
medicines to cure her...
I must help Sapphire's mother!
Make way, people!
I must rush to the Palace!
- Halt!
- Let me through!
I know the Palace as if
it were my own home!
And this is the shortest way!
The Queen is about to pass away!
- What was that?
- Excuse me!
How dare you? Why don't
you watch where you are going?
I'm sorry, but I'm in a hurry!
What...?
Mother...
Mother, I beg you, don't die!
Sapphire, I am sure that
your mother can be saved!
- Really?
- Of course!
I will ask the Lady of the Heavens
to grant this favor for her.
Lady of the Heavens!
Sapphire's mother is sick!
Help her, please! Save her!
I know you can do it, if you wish!
I am Lily!
Tink, I haven't seen you for a long time,
what have you called me for?
Hello, Lily! The Queen is dying
from a malignant fever.
I need the magic flower,
only with it can she be cured!
I understand! Which of you is the one
who loves the Queen the most,
- climb onto my back.
- I will come! I am her daughter!
Climb onto your back?
But how do I do it?
But this is a flying horse!
Yes, I am a flying horse.
You're surprised, right?
My name is Lily
and I am in the service of Venus.
You know, it is she who has power
over love and life.
Power over love and life?
Be careful, though,
because Venus is very vain!
She cares a lot about her beauty and
doesn't want anyone more beautiful than her!
We will arrive at her
dwelling soon, Princess.
Look! That is her Temple!
How wonderful! I have never
smelled such an intense fragrance!
They are the flowers of love for friends...
...and all living
creatures are her friends!
Those others, on the other hand,
are the flowers of love for enemies.
Those over there are the flowers
of a mother's love for her child.
- And those are...
- That's enough, Lily!
You are Sapphire, right?
Yes! I am here to ask you for
a magic flower for my mother.
I know. And I also know that you aren't
a Prince, but a Princess!
Lily, bring me the flower
of rebirth immediately!
Yes, ma'am.
You are a beautiful girl
I see that you are indeed very pretty!
Here it is, ma'am!
This is the flower of rebirth
and it will heal your mother!
I don't know how to thank you
for your help!
- You want it, don't you?
- Yes, I need it!
I am willing to do anything to have it.
Even giving your beauty
in exchange for the flower?
- What?!
- Don't you think you're asking too much?
You shut up, Lily! Sapphire, what
would you say if I made you ugly...
...in exchange for this flower?
- Make me ugly?
So, what do you decide?
Yes or no?
Go ahead and take my beauty!
I don't care about becoming ugly,
- if I can have that flower.
- Ah, is that so?
So you prefer to become ugly?
Then get ready!
Give me all your beauty,
Princess Sapphire!
Now go home!
Farewell, Princess!
You have the flower, but
you will be ugly forever!
Look, she is coming to! She is
already less pale than before!
Princess, your mother's
fever has broken!
Sapphire...
Sapphire, come near me,
my dear daughter, please!
Come on, Sapphire,
why are you hiding?
You scared me
with that mask!
Why do you have a mask, Sapphire?
Oh, mother...
Sapphire!
There is a spy in the castle!
Arrest her!
Why has Venus treated me
so cruelly,
even though she has power
over love and life?
- Surrender! You are surrounded!
- Wait!
What are you doing? I am Princess
Sapphire, don't you recognize me?
If you are really Prince Sapphire,
show us, take off your mask!
- But I...
- If you don't do it, it means...
...that you are certainly a spy
from another country!
It's not true! Believe me, I am
truly Princess Sapphire!
It's not true, kill him!
Don't let him escape!
Fire!
He escaped! Get him!
- Quick, this way!
- Let's search for him!
- He escaped that way!
- There he is!
- Let's run!
- Quick, chase him!
- Surrender, you scoundrel!
- I am Sapphire, believe me!
So much the worse for you!
Let's kill her! Filthy spy!
Stop it!
I am Sapphire!
Halt! Stop it!
It really is Prince Sapphire!
Opal! Opal!
Watch out, Opal!
Away, Opal!
I'm worried! I wonder where my
dear Sapphire could have gone...!
My poor child!
Laugh! Go ahead and laugh, if you're
satisfied with what you've done to me!
- Help! Help!
- Watch out!
- Help!
- I'll give you a hand!
Help me!
- Where am I?
- I'm glad you've recovered!
- Are you the one who helped me?
- Yes!
I thank you from the bottom
of my heart. Where am I now?
- You're in a village church.
- Really?!
My name is Riccardo and I am
the Prince of the Land of Troubles!
- And what about you, what is your name?
- Call me Pierre!
- Tell me, what happened to you?
- Nothing!
It looks like you have a problem!
You shouldn't be walking,
it's still too early!
Hey, you're wearing a mask!
Why are you wearing it?
Well, you see...
You must certainly have a good reason.
You can take it off! Tell me what it is!
Don't ask me questions, please!
I owe you my life
and I am very grateful to you!
Would you like to come to my Kingdom
and be a guest in my castle?
Sapphire, where could you be now?
I wish you would come home and not
leave me so worried about you!
Your Majesty, the cold air
is not good for you,
- you are still convalescing!
- That's true.
Your daughter
will surely return home!
I'm sure she'll return!
But I would so love to have wings...
...like a bird,
so I could fly to find her!
My castle is down there!
The people at the castle might
be frightened to see me with you.
I don’t care
about what people might say.
You are my guest! Let's go!
Look to your right.
There is the Land of Troubles!
- Who goes there?
- I am Prince Richard, open up!
If I heard correctly, Richard
has returned! Open the gate!
Richard, where have you been
all this time?
Hello, Donald! I’ve been out for
a long walk!
Who is that guy
you’ve got with you?
He’s a friend of mine and he’ll be staying
at the castle. His name is Pierre!
But he's wearing a mask!
Tell me,
do you want to take off that mask?
What are you waiting for?
Don't you know
that it's not good manners..
...to keep a mask on
when introducing yourself?
Well?! Either you're an arrogant type..
...or no one taught you
the rules of good manners!
Leave him alone, Donald! He's a good
guy and he saved my life!
It's not like you think! There's a
reason why he wears a mask!
Did you hear that, Jan?
He has a specific reason, she says!
What have you come here for,
you shady suspicious character?
Listen, both of you, stop it! He's
not a suspicious character at all!
- Now let us pass, Jan!
- Jan strong!
- If Jan doesn't want to, no one passes!
- You'd better tell him to get out of the way!
Wait, I want to take off your mask!
- Stop it, Donald, don't touch him!
- Riccardo!
You must be a spy from an enemy country!
I want to see your face! If
you don't take it off, I will!
Donald, stop it, I said!
Enough! Leave him alone!
He's a kind boy,
isn't that enough?
He is not what you think!
Donald, leave him alone!
Don't treat him like that,
he hasn't done anything wrong to you..
...and he saved my life!
- Damn it!
You have proven
to be a real spy!
No! I really...
You took advantage
of my brother's kindness.
...to enter the castle.
Jean, hit him!
Yes! Jan kill too!
Run, Pierre, don't wait for him!
That big brute is very dangerous!
Soldiers, close the gate!
- Dammit!
- Now you can no longer escape!
Stop it, Jan! Donald, that's enough!
Make him stay still!
Jan kill!
Look at the situation
that girl has gotten herself into!
Soon she won't just be ugly
in the face,
but her body will also be full
of scars. Well, too bad for her!
I am lost!
Father in heaven,
listen to me, I beg of you!
Protect Sapphire
wherever she has ended up!
- But you're Lily!
- Yes! Hop on my back!
- I found out where Sapphire is!
- What?!
Hold on tight!
My goodness, it's so cold!
And it's snowing, too! Lily,
can you tell me where he is?
- He's in the Land of Troubles!
- Is this country far away?
Quite a bit, but we'll get
there soon. Hold on tight!
Jan kill!
Like this!
No!
My sword!
Jan, kill him now!
Opal!
Be careful, Pierre!
Don't go that way!
Jan wins now!
Open up! What harm have I done to you?
Let me out!
I will let you out
only if you take off your mask!
Take off your mask
and show us your face!
- Don't worry, I'll take it off her!
- What a beautiful woman!
But this is Opal!
What happened, Opal?
Wake up, regain your strength!
Where is Sapphire?
- Quick, show me where she is!
- This man has fainted too!
But soon they will both
recover! Look over there!
There are footprints
going to that small door!
Venus, why do you treat me
with such cruelty?
- Because you are too beautiful!
- But if I am now the ugliest..
...of all women? - No!
You are still too beautiful in your soul!
Therefore I will also change your heart.
In fact, a girl...
...with an ugly heart
cannot help but become ugly!
Now come out of there!
Keep in mind that your mother
could become very ill again,
if you do not obey me!
Oh, mother, what can I do?
It's no use crying.
Resign yourself!
Stop it, Venus, don't act like
this! Why are you being so mean?
Don't meddle in things that
don't concern you, Tink!
But Sapphire is my best friend!
And besides, the Lord is angry
with you for your selfishness!
You haven't told him
everything, I hope, right, Tink?
No, I haven't told him
anything, but he knows anyway!
You brat! This will teach
you to be so impertinent!
You are not a Goddess, you
are a demon! A horrible demon!
No, I am Venus, the
Goddess of beauty...
...who can dispose of the love
and the lives of common mortals!
Everything that is
beautiful belongs to me!
So I also have the right
to make the beautiful ugly!
Now, Sapphire, I want you
to be ugly in face and soul!
Yes! The ugliest in the world!
Venus! Venus!
Did I not tell you to watch
over beauty, love, and life?
Yes, of course, Father!
It seems to me, instead, that you play...
...with people's beauty
in a very selfish way!
Therefore you yourself shall become ugly!
That way you will know how
the people you have hurt feel!
No, I don't want to become ugly!
Forgive me, Father, I won't do it anymore!
Oh...! No!
Look, Venus has
become a little pig.
Sapphire has fainted!
Sapphire, wake up!
Tink, I don't want
to see anyone anymore!
I am the ugliest in the world!
I don't care if you're ugly! I am
your friend and I will always love you!
- Thank you.
- Now take off your mask.
Please, don't run away
if my face scares you.
Am I that ugly?
Hooray!
You are exactly the same as before!
- You have the same face!
- The same face?
Thank you!
Don't hold it against me
if I hid my identity from you
It doesn't matter, Sapphire.
I will never forget you!
I am very sorry, Princess
I hope that, despite everything,
you will return.
Jean is very sorry!
Damn, you're so heavy!
But are you sure
that you are really Venus?
Sapphire, go home without me.
I am going to Heaven to ask
the Lord to forgive Venus!
Riccardo, Donald, Jean...
Goodbye, friends!
- Bye, Sapphire! See you soon!
- Bye! Bye!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP